# **Mohammed ALI**

#### **SUMMARY**

I am enthusiastically applying for the Data engineer job with 2 years of experience in working in data science and software development with a strong background in computer sciences, database and operating systems and machine learning.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Software Engineer - Sep 2021- Sep 2022

- Back-end engineer in IQ system solution 2021-2022
  - o Developing rental house application using Django
  - o Data modeling, Data designing and Testing

## Flutter Developer - Android, Jan 2021- Aug 2021

• Creating Android Apps using Flutter for Nasser's group, Yemen - Ibb

#### **CERTIFICATION**

- Cloud Data Engineer Professional Certificate
- Machine learning Andrew Ng
- IBM Data Engineering Professional Certificate 5 Courses
- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate 5 courses.

#### **Projects**

- Smart recipe system using (Python| Django| MySQL, DeepLearning)
  - It suggests users recipes according to their ingredients
  - It's done with three of my classmate as a design project
- Fake news classification using Naive bayes from scratch in python.
- Implementing **k-nearest neighbor** vs **logistic regression** algorithms from scratch in Python
- Web scraping + data analytics + automation

I have made web scraping for eight Turkish newspaper websites and get data dynamically and store them in MongoDB. Then I cleaned the collected data, did analysis, and plot graphs for changing the news by time. I also automated the operations using shell script to run after 10 minutes and store data in MongoDB

ETL using Python and shell script in Ubuntu
 Automate the pipeline for data workflow using shell script in Linux

- +90 531 504 1442
- mmomen574@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

# Hacettepe University, Computer Engineering

Ankara city, Turkey

# **SKILLS**

- Python, Java, C, Dart, shell scripts
- ETL pipelines, Data factory
- Spark, Airflow,
- SQL, NoSQL
- Django, Mysql, postgresql,
  Mangodb,
- GCP, AWS(Basics)
- Machine learning
- Git & Github
- Web scraping
- APIs
- Linux
- Data analytics
- Flutter

# **Hoppies**

- Camping
- Running
- Reading